<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | EMMA</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>First EMMA workshop at TUM</title>
      <link>/post/first-emma-workshop-at-tum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/first-emma-workshop-at-tum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;December 10, 2019 was a special day for Maximilian Pfertner’s PhD project EMMA – &amp;ldquo;Empowering Multimodal and Intermodal Accessibility Analysis&amp;rdquo;: Seven international experts joined us for the first expert workshop within our project funded by Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG) - German Research Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We presented our analysis of commuters who have changed their workplace location, to find out if this location alone shapes the daily commute (spoiler: it does!). The paper with all the details is currently under review – stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with our guests, we came to the conclusion that it is crucial to look at the workplace locations in order enable sustainable mobility in a region. EMMA’s approach to include intermodality in accessibility analysis is important for a better understanding of the real-life accessibility and mobility behavior of workers while opening up new ways to look at the potential impacts of intermodal services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to our experts Daniel Krajzewicz, Alain L&amp;rsquo;Hostis, Rolf Moeckel, Klaus Noekel, Marcus Peter, Cecília Silva, and David Vale!  We are looking forward to a second workshop in December!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EMMA’s next step is the development of an open, intermodal accessibility model for the Munich region, powered by OpenTripPlanner, PostGIS, and RStats – see the picture below for a sneak peek. We are thrilled to share more with the community soon!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-example-of-an-accessibility-map-for-bikeride&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/bikeandrideaccessibility.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Example of an accessibility map for Bike&amp;amp;Ride&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/bikeandrideaccessibility.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Example of an accessibility map for Bike&amp;amp;Ride
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-03-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-03-launch/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;hi-there.&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Hi there.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the brand new home of the EMMA project on intermodal and multimodal workplace accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;i-am-not-sure-what-to-write-though.&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I am not sure what to write though.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for coming to my TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
