<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | EMMA</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal accessibility of workplaces by time of day</title>
      <link>/post/changes-in-accessibility-during-a-workday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/changes-in-accessibility-during-a-workday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opendata-oepnv.de/ht/de/willkommen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official nation-wide GTFS dataset for Germany&lt;/a&gt; has been a game changer for all kinds of public transport analysis recently. Within EMMA, we use a filtered version of this dataset for the region in OpenTripPlanner. The timetable-based accuracy of the data allows a very detailed look at the changes in accessibility over time due to variations in the public transport supply. We would like to illustrate this using TUM&amp;rsquo;s main campus in the center of Munich and the Garching Campus, which is north of the City, connected with a subway line.&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tum-stammgelänge-in-maxvorstadt&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_stammgelaende.gif&#34; data-caption=&#34;TUM Stammgelänge in Maxvorstadt&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_stammgelaende.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    TUM Stammgelänge in Maxvorstadt
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blue isochrones show the area from where you could reach the TUM campus within 30 minute with public transport at the given time of day (on a Wednesday). You can see some headway-related flickering during the day, but between the early morning until the late evening, the area is relatively stable. A dense network of multiple public transport lines, from buses, to trams, subways, and regional trains (&amp;ldquo;S-Bahn&amp;rdquo;) ensures a good accessibility of this location during most of the day. 
How does a similar map look for the example of Garching?&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tum-campus-garching-hochbrück&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_garching.gif&#34; data-caption=&#34;TUM Campus Garching-Hochbrück&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_garching.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    TUM Campus Garching-Hochbrück
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might have expected, the isochrones are generally smaller, and much more narrow shaped along the North-South corridor. This is where the subway runs, the dominating public transport supply in the area. The effect of some bus lines is visible with the &amp;ldquo;islands&amp;rdquo; that appear on the map from time to time. Interestingly, there are some periods at night where there is no public transport on the campus at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-we-quantify-and-visualize-these-results&#34;&gt;How can we quantify and visualize these results?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following graph shows the number of people who can reach the locations by time of day - again within 30 minutes of public transport (and a max. walk distance of 800m).&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-comparison-of-both-locations&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_graph.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Comparison of both locations&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/2020-06-26_graph.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Comparison of both locations
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The striking difference in absolute numbers is not unexpected, given the locations. Some observations beyond this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The night shutdown from 2:00 - 5:00 is affecting Garching more than the main campus, where some supply is available 24/7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can identify (in the main campus mainly) the increased supply during the peak hours (roughly 7:00- 9:00  and 16:00 - 19:00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-this-imply-for-workplace-locations&#34;&gt;What does this imply for workplace locations?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, one has to understand that on the Garching Campus, there are mainly university buildings and other research institutions, but no housing at all. Thus, effects like the complete shutdown of public transport at night does not have a negative impact on this location at the moment. However, it does show that in the case of structural changes to the locations, adaptions will be necessary.&lt;br&gt;
Within EMMA, we can repeat a similar analysis in more depth e.g. for workplace locations, where a 24/7 accessibility is important (such as hospitals, factories with night shifts, &amp;hellip;) and generate recommendations for the further development.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First EMMA workshop at TUM</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-10-first-emma-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-12-10-first-emma-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;December 10, 2019 was a special day for Maximilian Pfertner’s PhD project EMMA – &amp;ldquo;Empowering Multimodal and Intermodal Accessibility Analysis&amp;rdquo;: Seven international experts joined us for the first expert workshop within our project funded by Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG) - German Research Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We presented our analysis of commuters who have changed their workplace location, to find out if this location alone shapes the daily commute (spoiler: it does!). The paper with all the details is currently under review – stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with our guests, we came to the conclusion that it is crucial to look at the workplace locations in order enable sustainable mobility in a region. EMMA’s approach to include intermodality in accessibility analysis is important for a better understanding of the real-life accessibility and mobility behavior of workers while opening up new ways to look at the potential impacts of intermodal services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to our experts Daniel Krajzewicz, Alain L&amp;rsquo;Hostis, Rolf Moeckel, Klaus Nökel, Marcus Peter, Cecília Silva, and David Vale!  We are looking forward to a second workshop in December!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EMMA’s next step is the development of an open, intermodal accessibility model for the Munich region, powered by OpenTripPlanner, PostGIS, and RStats – see the picture below for a sneak peek. We are thrilled to share more with the community soon!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-example-of-an-accessibility-map-for-bikeride&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/bikeandrideaccessibility.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Example of an accessibility map for Bike&amp;amp;Ride&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/bikeandrideaccessibility.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Example of an accessibility map for Bike&amp;amp;Ride
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
